--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 潇妹纸
时间轴: 潇妹纸
翻译: 苏菲 SceneryJuly Being 潇妹纸 戴蜀
校对: 岸 从OSU滚蛋的雕
达芬奇恶魔 第一季 第1集
要跟我一起抽吗 达芬奇?
Will you smoke with me, Da Vinci?
那要看里面装的是什么了
Well, that depends on what's in the pipe.
烟草混着圣诞玫瑰
It is a mixture of tobacco and black hellebore
据说可让人产生幻觉
and is rumored to induce visions
召唤出恶魔
and summon demons.
全是无稽之谈
Well, I believe in neither.
那你又何必这么努力克制呢?
Then why do you struggle so hard to keep both at bay?
历史就如同武器一般 被那些意欲掩盖真相的人
History is a lie that has been honed like a weapon
肆意改动 只剩谎言
by people who have suppressed the truth.
你注定会学会那些
The knowledge you are destined to learn
颠覆事物既定秩序的知识
will upend the established order of things.
你怎么知道?
How could you possibly know that?
你应该听过 '时间是一条河流'吧?
You have heard the phrase 'Time is a river'?
是的
Yes.
但大多数人没有理解到 这条河流是环形的
What most fail to grasp is that the river is circular.
每个人的死亡都开启了
One man's death opens a doorway
另一个人重生的大门
to the birth of the next.
你想知道这道重生之门
Would you like to know how
是如何开启的吗?
this particular doorway opened?
想
Yes.
先提醒你一句
Be forewarned, then.
并非所有大门都通向光明
Some doorways lead into darkness.
4天前
走吧 孩子 把衣服穿上!
Out you go, boy. Get on with you!
走吧! 快走!
Go on! Go on!
奇高!
Cicco!
- 今天星期几?  - 棕榈主日(复活节前的星期日)
- What day is it today?  - Palm Sunday.
该死
Oh, balls.
夫人和您的子民都已经在教堂了
The Duchess and your children are already at the church.
给我煮些鸡蛋吧
Could you round me up some coddled eggs?
我宿醉得厉害 肚子里翻江倒海的
I have a beastly hangover and my bowels are in a tumble.
我很快就穿好
I'll be dressed in but a minute.
大家不必拘礼 我来了!
At ease, people, I've arrived!
走开 混账东西 这是我的时刻
Be gone, you artless fuckwit. This is my moment.
经密令指示
And thanks to the Secret Archives,
这将是你最后的时刻!
it's the last you will ever enjoy!
莱昂纳多 告诉我一个秘密吧
Tell me a secret, Leonardo.
你最早的记忆... 是什么?
What was your... earliest memory?
或者 换个问题
Or better yet,
你最害怕的是什么?
your greatest fear?
对我来说...
In my case...
这两个问题差不多
the two go hand-in-hand.
我那时...
I was...um...
我那时才六个月
I was six months old.
没人能记得这么小时候的事
No-one remembers back that far.
也许我比较特别吧
Well, perhaps I'm unique, then.
- 好吧  - 我母亲...
- Oh.  - My mother... um...
带着我去田里 将我放在摇篮里
put me in a cradle out in the field.
一只猎鹰飞了下来 我还记得
And a falcon flew down. I can still recall it.
它就栖在那儿 看着我
It just perched there, looking at me
仿佛想要揭示
almost as if it were trying to reveal
什么秘密
some kind of mystery.
母亲赶走了它
My mother drove it away.
虽然我的记性很好
Yet, as clear as that memory is,
但是我唯一记不得的...
the one thing I can never recall...
就是我母亲的脸
is my mother's face.
我能画出所有看过的东西 甚至那些转瞬即逝的
I can draw anything I've seen, even in passing.
但每次回想我母亲 都没有一丁点印象
But when it comes to my mother, all I see is a void.
自从那夜她消失后 我一直...
She disappeared that night and I've been...
努力回想她的样子
trying to recall her face ever since.
所有的男人都在寻找自己的母亲
All men are searching for their mothers.
所以才会流连于女人的大腿之间
That's what guides you between our thighs.
我雇你来当模特的 瓦妮莎
I pay you to pose, Vanessa.
不是让你来窥探我心底的
Not to plumb the innermost depths of my character.
你希望我在你面前赤裸裸
If you expect me to bare my figure for you,
我也希望你能对我坦诚灵魂
I expect you to bare your soul in return.
告诉我吧 你最害怕什么?
So, tell me, is there nothing else you fear?
不够完美
Only imperfection.
大师! 大师!
Maestro! Maestro!
你迟到了 尼科
You're late, Nico.
是你迟到了 维罗吉欧正找你呢
You're late. Verrocchio's been looking for you.
让他等吧 我们来做一个实验
Well, he can wait. We've an experiment to conduct.
这个实验少了你不行
You're meant to play a principal role in it.
- 来吧!  - 你好
- Come on!  - Hello.
那叫胸部 尼科 每个女人都有的
They're called breasts, Nico. Every woman possesses them.
尼科! 那是瓦妮莎
Nico! That's Vanessa.
她刚从圣安东尼修道院解放出来
She's newly liberated from the Convent of St Anthony.
过来帮我
Now help me do this.
绑上那个背带
Climb into that harness.
今天
Hey today,
我们要尝试证明 这个风筝
we are attempting to ascertain whether or not
能否提供足够的空气阻力
this kite can provide the necessary wind resistance
来支撑你的重量
to support your weight.
大师 如果它不能呢?
Well, Maestro, what if it can't?
瓦妮莎 可以跳会儿舞吗?
Vanessa, do you mind just dancing about for a moment?
看见了吗? 那些飘动的丝带
You see? Those weighted ribbons
我能够因此计算出
allow me to calculate the strength
风力和风向
and direction of the wind.
现在 我估算... 风力大约20节
In this case, I would say... it's about 20 knots
风向...
and shifting...
北方
westerly.
等等 大师! 万一你算错了呢?
Wait, Maestro! What if your calculations are wrong?
等等 等等 大师! 大师 求你了 快停下!
Wait, wait, Maestro! Oh, Maestro, please, please stop!
等等 大师 大师!
Oh, wait, Maestro. Maestro!
哦 我的天哪 快停下!
Oh, my God, please!
看啊!
Yes!
你飞起来了 尼科!
You're flying, Nico!
大师!
Maestro-o-o!
太完美了!
It's perfect!
太高了! 别这么高
You're too high! Not so high.
尼科!
Nico!
成功了! 成功了 大师!
It works! It works, Maestro!
我从未怀疑过
I never had any doubts.
天哪 我讨厌这个地方
Oh, God, I hate this place.
什么? 除了佛罗伦萨还有其他地方
What? Where else could we practice our flights
能让我们飞吗?
but in Florence?
要是在其他地方 我们早就因此
Anywhere else, we'd just be burnt at the stake
被施以火刑了
for our efforts.
这儿呢? 我只是一个思想自由的异教徒
But here? I'm just another free-thinking heretic.
混沌 文化
Chaos. Culture.
在这高墙之内 所有的一切都是自由的
It's all celebrated within these walls.
佛罗伦萨对它的人民只有一个要求
Florence only demands one thing of its people.
真正的觉醒
To be truly awake.
此女只应天上有
Like that angelic vision.
别妄想了 那是卢克蕾齐娅・多纳蒂
Don't even think about it. That's Lucrezia Donati.
洛伦佐・德・美第奇的情妇 我很清楚她是谁
Lorenzo de Medici's mistress. I'm well aware of who she is.
如果他抓到你在看她
He'll break you on the wheel,
会把你五马分尸的
if he catches you looking at her.
但如果是她在看我呢?
But what if she's caught looking at me?
米兰那边传来坏消息 尼科
Bad tidings from Milan, Nico.
你怎么知道?
How can you tell?
骑士外套上的图案是无毒环纹蛇
That serpent on the rider's surcoat is the Biscione,
斯福尔扎家族的族徽
the Sforza family emblem.
如果他带来的是好消息 他应该戴上
If he was bringing good news, he'd have been dressed
更传统的红白相间的米兰徽章
in the more traditional red and white shield of Milan.
不管是什么消息
Whatever the message is,
洛伦佐都会不高兴的
Lorenzo won't be happy with it.
出去!
Out!
出去! 全部出去!
Out! All of you!
洛伦佐? 洛伦佐!
Lorenzo? Lorenzo!
米兰公爵死了
The Duke of Milan is dead.
- 被刺杀的  - 谁干的?
- Assassinated.  - By whose hand?
- 威士康蒂和另外两个人  - 那是荣誉谋杀了
- Visconti and two others.  - An honor killing, then.
他们说 公爵强暴了自己的侄女
They say the Duke deflowered his niece.
斯福尔扎是欲求不满的猪
Sforza was a pig of epic appetites.
是 但他也是我们的猪!
Yes, but he was our pig!
我觉得梵蒂冈是幕后黑手
I sense the Vatican's hand behind this.
时机把握得太准确
The timing is just too perfect.
如果你是对的 这会打破意大利的势力平衡 洛伦佐
If you're right, this upsets the balance of power in Italy, Lorenzo.
哦 神啊 贝奇 这不仅仅是打破
Oh, by God, Becchi, this more than upsets.
这简直就是完全摧毁
This all but decapitates the concept
对它公然挑衅!
and shits down its throat!
我们需要争取公众的支持
We need to shore up public support.
复活节假期快到了
Easter holiday is nearly upon us.
我们办一个嘉年华
Let's throw a carnival.
让佛罗伦萨的人民像庆祝
Allow the people of Florence to celebrate
大斋节的到来一样欢送它的结束
the end of Lent as they do its arrival.
盛况越空前
The more flamboyant the pageantry,
显得我们越强
the stronger we appear.
我们不是爱炫耀的孔雀 朱利亚诺
We're not fucking peacocks, Giuliano.
嘉年华是不错
Carnival is all well and good,
但如果没有强大的后台
but if it has no teeth behind it,
我们同样是在自取灭亡
we might as well slit our own throats.
你害怕吗?
Are you frightened?
不 尊敬的教皇
No, Most Holy Father.
说谎是一种罪 我的孩子
Lying is a sin, my dear boy.
它会让我们失去神的恩宠
It separates us from God's grace.
是的 我害怕
Yes, I'm frightened.
这也是谎话 对吧?
But that's also a lie, isn't it?
至少 不全是真话
At least, a partial one.
也许这是可赦之罪
A venial sin, perhaps.
那么...
So...
哪一种回答才是真的?
which statement is correct?
嗯?
Hm?
说啊 孩子
Speak, child.
难道你不想上天堂?
Don't you want to enter heaven?
正确的回答应该是...
The proper answer would be...
请留步! 教皇禁止任何人打扰
Please! His Holiness has forbidden any visitors.
我们的人成功了 大人!
Our men succeeded, Your Grace!
斯福尔扎死了
Sforza is dead.
是时候拿下佛罗伦萨了 教皇大人
Florence is ripe for the picking, Your Eminence.
相信我
Trust me.
为什么这么说?
You know this how?
洛伦佐身边有我的人
Because I have an agent within Lorenzo's ranks.
美第奇家族要举办一个嘉年华
The Medicis are throwing a carnival,
想借此来赢得人民的支持
in a pathetic bid to win the people's favor.
他们不堪一击 陛下
They're weak, Your Holiness.
这是您一举拿下他们的好机会
This is your chance to strike.
不是我 侄子
Not mine, Nephew.
是上帝
The Lord's.
还有一件事要告诉您
There is another reason for haste.
土耳其人已经到佛罗伦萨了
The Turk has arrived in Florence.
他在找叶之书
He's after the Book of Leaves.
真的很抱歉
I am truly sorry.
为什么?
Why?
因为你听到的太多了
Because you can't have heard this.
你们准备好鸽子表演了吗?
Do you have the plans for the colombina or not?
是的
We do.
十分惊艳
And they're breathtaking.
那就把这些神奇的效果展现出来
Then produce these miraculous renderings
让我们评估一下
and let us evaluate them.
很遗憾...
Unfortunately...
我不能
I can't.
因为它们不存在!
Because they don't exist!
神啊 如果你觉得你能欺骗
By God, if you think you can defraud
美第奇家族...
the House of Medici...
不 不 不 它们存在 我向你保证!
No, no, no, they do exist, I promise you!
它们在这个箱子里
They're in this chest.
- 打开  - 它被锁上了
- Open it.  - It's locked.
好啊 那我用剑劈开它
Well, then, I'll take my sword to it.
如果强行打开这个箱子的话
The chest is rigged to explode
它就会爆炸
if anyone tampers with it.
你疯了?
Are you mad?
怎么会有人造出这种可怕的发明?
Why would anyone engineer such an infernal contrivance?
当然是为了保护我的创意
To protect my ideas, obviously.
先生们 这位是莱昂纳多・达芬奇
Gentlemen, Leonardo Da Vinci.
啊 我听说过你
Ah, I've heard of you.
他们说你是个自由思想家
They say you're quite the free-thinker.
- 你来晚了  - 来吃个葡萄
- You're late.  - Grape.
好! 佛罗伦萨长官
So! The First Citizen of Florence
渴求我们给他制造出一只鸽子
is desperate for us to fashion him a colombina.
"渴求"说得太过了
"Desperate" is a strong word.
可我说的是事实
And yet it happens to be the word I used.
让我们回想一下
But let's review.
每年复活节 佛罗伦萨的街头
Every Easter, a grand procession makes its way
都会有浩大的游行队伍
through the streets of Florence,
走向大教堂
terminating at the cathedral.
你为什么非要说这些
Why do you insist on stating
连三岁小孩都知道的废话?
what every child of three already knows?
你为什么非要打断我?
Why do you insist on interrupting me?
我有我的方法论 你可以听我的
I have a methodology. We can follow it.
或者咱们也可以打一架
Or we can flail about.
不说话我就默认你们听我的了 那我继续
I'll take your silence as a vote for the former. Onward.
在人群上空 一只机械鸽子
At the culmination of mass, a mechanical dove,
也就是这只鸽子 带着牵线 从圣坛上
the colombina, is flown from the altar on a wire.
翱翔到广场上空
Out into the public square it soars.
点燃一车的烟花
It ignites a cart full of fireworks.
群众开始欢庆 戴上面具
The Republic celebrates, they don masks.
喝酒狂欢...
They engage in drunken revelry. Now...
几年来 美第奇家族一直在雇佣
For years, the House of Medici has contracted
低劣的工坊制造这仪式鸽子
with inferior workshops to produce said ceremonial dove.
但是今年
But, this year,
不出我所料的话
if I am to understand the politics afoot,
这种低劣的情景
the same shoddy pageantry
不会再发生了
just won't do.
从没有人对我们的鸽子吹毛求疵
No-one's carped about our dove before.
你们管那个叫"鸽子" 简直是对鸟类的侮辱
To call your previous efforts 'a dove' is to insult the entire avian class.
够了! 快给我们展示你这破玩意吧
Enough! Just show us the damn thing.
好吧
All right.
这是个四分之一比例模型
That is but a quarter-scale model.
来
There.
这个真的很漂亮啊
It's a thing of beauty, I'll grant you that.
没错 30弗罗林 你就能带走了
Yes, and it can be yours for 30 florins.
- 30弗罗林?  - 没错
- 30?  - Yeah.
合同上写的是12弗罗林
The contract stated 12.
那种鸟需要绳子牵引才行
That was for a bird that needed a guide wire.
这个则不需要那种东西
This miracle requires no such handicap.
你的作品令人印象深刻
Your work is impressive.
但是价钱太不合理了
But the price is too steep.
- 30弗罗林很便宜啊  - 30弗罗林简直是抢劫!
- 30 florins is a bargain.  - 30 florins is sodomy!
或许我应该
Perhaps I should be negotiating
和你的哥哥谈价
with your older brother instead.
天啊 贝奇
For God's sake, Becchi,
付钱给这贱民 赶紧了结这事算了
just pay the degenerate and be done with it.
算你赢了 艺术家
You win, artista.
按照佣金的惯例
As is customary with commissions,
我们先付一半定金 完工后再付另一半
we shall pay half now and half upon completion.
既然说到佣金...
While we're on the subject of commissions,
我听说 你们在找人给卢克蕾齐娅・多纳蒂画肖像
I'm told that there's an open one to paint Lucrezia Donati.
洛伦佐的情妇
Lorenzo's mistress.
专心于你的玩意和小把戏吧 达芬奇
Stick to your whirligigs and parlor tricks, Da Vinci.
想想伊卡洛斯的下场
Take a lesson from Icarus.
告诉我吧...
So, tell me...
你最害怕什么?
is there nothing else you fear?
你没事吧 莱昂纳多?
Are you all right, Leonardo?
只是个噩梦 安德里亚
It was just a nightmare, Andrea.
你噩梦做得太频繁了
You have them all too frequently.
我在计算上遇到了点问题 仅此而已
I'm having some issues with my mathematics, that's all.
问题?
Issues?
我不知道...
I'm not sure...
复活节前 能不能造出来那种鸽子
that the colombina will be flightworthy by Easter.
- 但那个模型...  - 那只是个模型
- But the model...  - Was a model.
当我按比例放大的之后
Once I scale up the dimensions,
计算就出问题了 真烦人
the calculations don't hold. It's annoying!
你抽鸦片没有用
Smoking opium won't help matters.
- 至少能让我清醒  - 它只能让你糊涂
- It clears my head.  - It clouds it.
你是谁? 我的保姆吗? 我要想的事情太多了 好吗?
What are you, my nursemaid? I think too much. All right?
我需要糊涂一下 不然我就要疯了
I need to dull my thoughts or I'll be eviscerated by them.
我觉得你现在应该
I would have thought that you would have
明白了吧!
understood that by now!
鸦片有药用价值
The tears of the poppy have medicinal properties.
- 埃及的祭司...  - 我们不在埃及
- The priests in Egypt...  - We are not in Egypt.
你也不是祭司
And you are no priest.
你很有天赋 莱昂
You have a gift, Leo.
可以说是个... 天才...
A kind of...genius...
我从未见过像你这样的人
the likes of which I've never seen.
正因如此 人们总会想方设法地消灭你
Because of that, people will always seek to destroy you.
拜托...
Please...
不要在自我毁灭 如他们所愿了
don't aid them in their endeavor.
- 这些椋鸟多少钱?  - 每只六铜钱
- How much for the starlings?  - Six denari apiece.
给你两铜钱 我都要了
I'll give you two soldi for the lot.
你在侮辱我吗?
Are you trying to offend me?
没有 要是我想侮辱你的话
No, if I was trying to offend you,
我会说你的臀部后
I'd comment on the scent of fecal matter
挂着粪便物
wafting from your hindquarters.
两铜钱到底行不行?
Do you want the soldi or not?
只有这么多钱 不要就算了
They're my last. I'm bored.
不 我不想带走这些鸟
No, I'm not interested in the birds.
听我的指挥把笼子打开
Just open the cage on my say-so.
他对飞行感兴趣 他想通过鸟找灵感
He's obsessed with flight. He studies them for inspiration.
开
Now.
恩? 如愿看到什么了吗?
Well? Did you see what you were hoping to?
还我一铜钱 我就告诉你
For one of my soldi back, I just might tell you.
好吧 告诉我
All right. Tell me.
我看到一个傻瓜不知道怎样谈价
I saw an idiot who doesn't know how to haggle.
看那边 尼科 她又来了
Look, Nico. There she is again.
她和洛伦佐在一起
Look at her with Lorenzo.
所有人都装得不知道两人上过床
Everyone pretending the two of them aren't fucking.
- 那不是你父亲吗?  - 他像寄生虫一样
- Isn't that your father?  - Crown Prince of parasites.
给洛伦佐当公证人
He serves as Lorenzo's notary.
来吧 尼科 咱们去凑凑热闹
Come on, Nico, let's stir the pot a little.
殿下!
Your Magnificence!
我叫莱昂纳多・达芬奇 您可能听说过我?
My name is Leonardo Da Vinci. Perhaps you've heard of me?
我在为您设计复活节的鸽子
I am designing your Easter colombina.
噢 对
Oh, yes.
你就是维罗吉欧雇佣的那个怪人
You're the eccentric that Verrocchio employs.
我是个艺术家 解剖学家
I'm an artist, yes, and an anatomist
还是个工程师
and an engineer of some note.
我记得我称呼你为"劫匪"吧
"Extortionist" is the word I recall using.
我谈价时很吝啬 没错
I drive a stiff bargain, it's true.
但事实上 我设计了
But the fact is, I have designed
许多更宏大的装置
a more ambitious series of devices
我知道您慧眼识珠
that I know your percipient mind
一定会感兴趣
will take an interest in.
躲开点 混蛋
Move along, vermin.
下次吧
Another time.
也许
Perhaps.
我伤心了 尼科
I'm wounded, Nico.
我要喝酒
I need wine.
生意怎么样 琐罗亚斯德?
How goes business, Zoroaster?
自从公爵死后 一直糟透了
Execrable, since the Duke's demise.
佛罗伦萨阴云密布
These are dark times for Florence.
比如那些涌进城的雇佣兵
Case in point. Those mercenaries flooding into town.
假如战争真的爆发
If war does break out,
他们是唯一能赚钱的人
they'll be the only ones gainfully employed.
说到赚钱
Speaking of employment,
兹托的农场有只牛犊长了两个头 刚出生就死了
a two-headed calf, stillborn on Zitto's farm.
如果你医学研究用的话 我可以给你弄来
I can procure it, if you like, for your medical studies.
上一次你送来的那具尸体都腐烂了
The last corpse was decomposing by the time I took a scalpel to it.
挖坟掘墓和捕鱼一样
Grave-robbing is like fishmongering.
每次都要靠运气
You're at the mercy of the day's catch.
吃猪肠吗?
Come on. A boar sausage?
你知道我是素食主义者
You know damn well that I am a vegetarian.
- 所以我才尽力腐化你  - 噢 我很容易腐化的
- So I keep hoping to corrupt you.  - Oh, I'm corruptible.
我只是不想吃长眼睛的东西
I just prefer not to eat anything with eyes.
- 土豆也会长眼睛  - 滚吧 尼科!
- Potatoes have eyes.  - Fuck off, Nico!
大师!
Maestro!
我能再为您做模特吗?
May I model for you again?
从没有人像您一样眼光独特
No-one looks at my form as you do.
我看什么都眼光独特
No-one looks at any form as I do.
想推销商品去博蒂切利那边吧
Go peddle your wares with Botticelli.
他容易上当
He's an easy mark.
模特? 那孩子只是个骗子
Model? That boy's nothing but a hustler
而且骗技很差
and an artless one at that.
但他眼神招人喜爱
But pleasing to the eye, nonetheless.
呸
Piss.
来 看一眼这个
Here. Have a gander at these.
我的最新爱好
My latest venture.
这是塔罗牌
They're called tarot cards.
用来占卜命运
They're used to divine fortunes.
来吧 尼科 抽一张 看看是否和你性情一致
Here. Pick one, Nico. We'll see if it squares with your temperament.
- 有意思 是魔术吧  - 是吗?
- Funny. It's a trick.  - Is it?
也许是远古力量和我的沟通呢?
Or am I simply channeling the powers of The Ancients?
你用这骗过多少女孩 琐罗?
How many women has that line worked on, Zo?
一大堆女孩 谢谢夸奖
A respectable amount. Thank you very much.
我也骗过很多男的
And a goodly number of gentlemen, as well.
塔罗牌不止能象征性情
But a card can symbolize not just one's temperament,
还能占卜命运
but one's fate.
你敢占卜你的吗?
Do you dare see yours?
告诉我 别隐瞒
Tell me. Don't hold back.
这张...
This one...
代表祭献
represents sacrifice.
在生与死之间游离 然后可能...
A suspension between life and death and then perhaps...
迎来伟大的觉醒
a great awakening.
我是个傻瓜
I'm an idiot.
那些雇佣兵 佛罗伦萨没有自己的军队
Those mercenaries. Florence has no army of its own.
所以那些佣兵才来卖命 对吧?
So they're here to sell their muscle. Right?
但要是有更加有利可图的方法呢?
But what if there was a more lucrative way to traffic in the Republic's unease?
- 比如?  - 我应该说自己...
- Like what?  - I should promote myself
去做军事工程师 而不是画家
as a military engineer, not a painter.
战争总是可以推动发展
War has always been the handmaiden of progress.
如果我想继续探索下去
If I want to explore my ideas,
我只要以防御佛罗伦萨为借口就可以了
I just need to cloak them in the guise of Florence's defense.
为什么那些夜巡长官在找那个人的麻烦?
Why are the officers of the night bothering that man?
他是土耳其异教徒 原因还不够明显吗?
He's a Turk, a heathen. Isn't that reason enough?
不要管
No.
这不关你的事 莱昂
No, this isn't your fight, Leo.
这种原因能阻止我吗?
When's that ever stopped me?
发生什么事了?
What seems to be the trouble here?
该干嘛干嘛去 画画的
Go back to your sketchbook, scribbler.
这没你的事
This isn't your concern.
你看 很不幸 恩...
You see, unfortunately, um...
我有种癖好
I have this character flaw
遇到不平的事我就忍不住要插手 所以...
that compels me to intervene whenever stupidity rears its head, so...
看到了吗? 太笨了
You see? Cos that was stupid.
因为你握得太松了
Cos your man's grip was too loose
现在你低头看时
and now he finds himself
才发现自己把剑丢了
staring down this handsome spada da filo.
这个更笨了
Even more stupidity.
你去打听打听
Cos if you'd just asked around,
所有人都说我双手灵巧
anyone will tell you that I'm ambidextrous
可以轻松地同时对付两个...
and perfectly capable of fighting two or...
甚至三个人
even three men simultaneously.
欺负别人去吧 德拉戈奈蒂
Bully someone else, Dragonetti.
你今晚失算了 艺术家
You've made a serious miscalculation tonight, artista.
反正又不是第一次了
It wouldn't be the first time.
- 你还好吧 先生?  - 我很好
- Are you all right, sir?  - I'm more than all right.
我是大地与星空之子
I am a son of Earth and Starry Heaven.
后天我就要回君士坦丁堡了
I return to Constantinople the day after tomorrow.
我住在黑天鹅旅店
But I am staying at the Inn of the Black Swan.
我离开之前来见见我...
Come see me before I leave...
大师
Maestro.
有点怪
A bit weird.
他给你的是什么?
What did he give you?
我觉得 是个提示
A tip, I think.
那是她妈妈
It was her mother.
屁股一样 脸可大不一样
The same arse, very different faces
然后 我认出来之后 还小吸了下她奶头
and, when I realized, I did a little sip on her tit.
扶着他 尼科 天啊 他一个人回不了家的
Take him, Nico. Jesus. He'll never make it home alone.
你确定吗 大师? 已经宵禁了 也许有强盗什么的
Are you sure, Maestro? It's after curfew and there are bound to be rogues about.
- 正好适合我 去吧!  - 听着 里奥
- Then I'll fit right in. Go!  - Listen, Leo.
什么?
What?
倒吊人那张卡 不是我特意弄的 是你自己选的
I didn't deal you the Hanged Man. That was all you.
那是个预兆 不是什么好兆头
It was an omen. It was just like the two-headed calf.
行了 我不信什么预兆
No, I don't believe in omens.
行了行了 你才会信 走吧
No. No, this is you. Go.
快走!
Go!
我知道是你 德拉戈奈蒂
I know it's you, Dragonetti.
之前的教训你还没接受啊?
Did you not learn your lesson earlier?
啊
Ah.
看来你接受了
I guess you did learn.
可以了
That's enough.
我早该知道
I should have known.
大家对你议论纷纷
People are talking about you.
就是没什么好评价
And not in a positive light.
我从不在乎别人怎么说我
I couldn't care less what they're saying about me.
我在乎!
I care!
我不能让你玷污家族的名声
I'll not have you tarnishing our family's name
油腔滑调 自我宣传 举止轻佻
with your flippant tone and your vulgar attempts at self-promotion.
那跟我脱离关系好了
Perhaps you should disown me, then.
你是我的长子
You're my first-born.
就算我想跟你脱离父子关系
And much as I may wish to disavow you,
我们的名声总是纠缠一起
our reputations are intertwined.
长子?
First-born?
你说得倒像是...
You say that as if...
我妻子 玛格丽特...
My wife, Margherita...
上周为我生了个儿子
bore me a son this past week.
一个合法继承人
A legitimate heir.
哦 向他表示哀悼
Well, my condolences to him.
不知道他什么时候才会开始痛恨自己的血统
I wonder how long it will take him to curse his lineage.
你不过是个私生子 社会地位就没什么可商量的了
As a bastard, your rank within the social order has been rigidly defined.
你最好老实地接受自己的地位
You should endeavor to remain within it.
离美第奇家族远点 莱昂纳多
Stay away from the Medicis, Leonardo.
- 这是最后一次警告了  - 省省吧
- I'll not warn you again.  - I'll wager you will.
你为什么总跟我作对?
Why do you have to make this so difficult?
这是我的天性! 我看到事物的本质
It's my nature! I see things as they are,
而不是表象
not as they might be.
你...
You...
心胸狭隘
are a petty man.
你... 没可能有所作为
And... you will never achieve greatness.
而我...
Where as I...
我已经有所作为了
I already have.
你现在跪在地牢里
You're kneeling in a dungeon.
还要继续挨打
About to be hit again and again.
打你的都是个中好手
By men who know how to hit.
你就这点作为了 莱昂纳多
That's what you've achieved, Leonardo.
再打一小时
Beat him for another hour,
然后跟其他垃圾一起扔到街上去
then toss him back onto the street with the rest of the garbage.
按住这小子的手
Hold out the scribbler's hand.
说真的 你看起来比我还要可怜了 所以...
To be fair, you actually look more wretched than I, so...
你厉害
well done.
还是去看看医生吧
Perhaps you should see a physician.
我没事
I'm fine.
噢 今天有个犹太人要被绞死
Oh, they're executing a Jew today.
很显然 他们抓到他闯入了西尔・达街的一家书店
Apparently, they caught him breaking into the book shop on the Via Dei Librai.
会是个不错的盛会
It should be good sport.
我不觉得一个人的死可以被称为盛会
I'm not sure a man's death should be characterized as sport.
这地方太晒了 我们换个阴凉点的地方吧?
This fucking spot is too sunny. Can't we move over into the shade?
- 不行  - 为什么?
- No.  - Why?
因为每天早上 就这个时候
Because every morning, at precisely this time,
卢克蕾齐娅・多纳蒂都会来这里买...
Lucrezia Donati comes to this exact spot to purchase...
鲜花
flowers.
瞧
There.
她很迷人 这点我赞同 但是...
She's appealing, I'll grant you that, but...
我宁肯跟那个没牙老巫婆睡一觉
I'd rather bed that old toothless hag over there.
你这纯属抬扛
Now you're just being contrary.
干漂亮女人不需要什么技巧
It takes no great skill to fuck a pretty face.
但要干丑女人 才真正是挑战
But a truly ugly woman, that actually requires discipline
听我说 朋友 搞得好的话
and, let me tell you, my friend, done right,
那可真是欲仙欲死
a transcendent experience.
尼科 把这给她送去
Nico, run this over to her.
确保她知道是谁送的
Make sure she knows where it's come from.
里奥 你到底在想些什么?
What the devil are you up to, Leo?
她要跟你说话
She wants to speak with you.
啊哈 告诉她 我忙着呢
Uh-huh? Well, tell her I'm busy.
干嘛不趁热打铁?
You're seriously not turning her down?
去跟她说 尼科 时机未到
Tell her, Nico. Timing is all.
他现在没空
He can't right now.
看哪 我们中的一个罪犯!
Behold, a criminal in our midst!
犹太人 又是犹太人!
A Jew, no less!
看着他跳! 看着他晃!
Watch him dance! Watch him dangle!
拿好你们的水果和石子!
Bring your fruit and small stones!
上帝保佑佛罗伦萨共和国!
God protect the Republic of Florence!
我是大地与星空之子
I am a son of Earth and Starry Heaven.
我渴了
I am thirsty.
求你了 从记忆之泉中
Please, give me something to drink
取水给我喝
from the Fountain of Memory.
大师 你没事吧?
Are you all right, Maestro?
我得走了
I need to leave.
这里住着个外国人吗? 一个土耳其人?
Is there a foreigner staying here, a Turkish man?
他说你可以到罗马遗迹去找他
He said you could find him at the Roman ruins,
就在城北
north of town.
达芬奇 和我一起抽吧?
Will you smoke with me, Da Vinci?
那要看烟管里装了什么
Well, that depends on what's in the pipe.
历史就如同武器一般
History is a lie that has been honed like a weapon
被那些意欲掩盖真相的人肆意改动 只剩谎言
by people who have suppressed the truth.
几百年后 你自己的历史
Centuries from now, your own history
也会被掩盖
will also be suppressed.
你怎么可能知道?
How could you possibly know that?
你听过这句话吗? "时间是一条河流"
You have heard the phrase "Time is a river"?
所不为人知的是
What most fail to grasp
河流是一个循环
is that the river is circular.
一个人死去...
One man's death...
为另一个人的降生敞开了大门
opens a doorway to the birth of the next.
我今天看到一个人被绞死了
I saw a man executed today.
他对我说了些话
He said something to me.
- 我是...  - 大地与
- I am...  - A son of Earth
星空之子
and Starry Heaven.
我渴了
I am thirsty.
求你了 从记忆之泉中
Please, give me something to drink
取水给我喝
from the Fountain of Memory.
这是一句祷词
It is an invocation.
我们同族之间
A way for members of our fraternity
互相辨认的暗语
to recognize one another.
我又不是你们一族
I'm not a member of your fraternity.
你确定吗?
Are you sure?
这座庙宇曾是一个宗教的礼拜堂
This temple was once a place of worship
而这个宗教 历史比基督教
for a religion that originated
更加久远
long before Christ.
我们被称为密特拉(波斯太阳神)之子
We are known as the Sons of Mithras.
大多数你们所谓的"进步"
Much of what you call 'progress'
不过都是些一度失落的回忆
has simply been a matter of remembering what was once forgotten.
这些知识都被记录在
This knowledge was set down
一本被称为"叶之书"的典籍里
in a compendium known as the Book of Leaves.
最近 关于这本书所在之处的种种线索 逐渐浮出水面
Recently, certain clues have surfaced regarding the Book's location.
阿乌拉罕・本・尤瑟夫被逮捕并处死前
Avraham ben Yosef was following those clues
就一直在追寻这些线索
when he was apprehended and put to death.
梵蒂冈的密令 不知你是否有所耳闻?
Perhaps you have heard of the Secret Archives the Vatican has assembled?
密令的管理人 叫卢珀・梅克里
Its curator is a man called Lupo Mercuri.
密特拉族人的叛徒
A fallen son of Mithras.
我们追求的是传播和保护知识
Where we seek to disseminate and preserve knowledge.
而他们篡改知识 限制知识传播
They seek to alter and suppress it.
我还是... 我还是不明白
I still... I still don't understand
这些跟我有什么关系
what any of this has to do with me.
你对你母亲... 有什么印象?
What do you know... about your mother?
几乎没有
Almost nothing.
她... 她失踪了
She... she disappeared.
- 她是个女仆  - 她是个奴隶
- She was a servant girl.  - She was a slave.
被强行从君士坦丁堡带走了
Taken from Constantinople against her will.
你是否记得...
Do you remember...
童年时代遭遇过的什么事故吗?
an incident that occurred in your childhood?
你一直压制这段记忆
You have suppressed it.
我小时候在芬奇
I was a boy in Vinci.
被派去寻找丢失的羊群
I'd been sent to fetch some sheep that had wandered off.
我发现了一个山洞
I found a cave.
我不敢进去 但...
I was scared to go inside, but...
但我很好奇
But I was curious.
还是冒险进去了
So I ventured in.
然后的事情... 我想不起来了
The next hours... are blank.
我记得...
I remember...
踉跄地走出来
stumbling out.
我的手上脸上...
My hands and face...
都沾满了血
were covered in blood.
不知何故...
And somehow...
我清楚那不是我的血
I knew it wasn't my own.
总有一天...
One day...
你将饮下记忆之泉的水...
you will sip from the Fountain of Memory...
想起更多你在洞中的经历
and learn more of what occurred in that cave.
到那一天 我们还会再见
When that day comes, we will meet again.
在那之前我应该怎么做?
What do I do till then?
寻找"叶之书"
Search for the Book of Leaves.
莱昂纳多 命运选择了你
Fate has chosen you, Leonardo.
- 我不相信命运  - 那就相信你自己
- I don't believe in fate.  - Then believe in yourself.
好吧 那么我该从何处开始寻找?
Well, where do I start my search, then?
从绞死的人入手 从灵魂深处入手
With the hanged man, the seat of the soul.
他已经为你打开了一扇门
He's already opened the door for you.
那我母亲?
And my mother?
她将在彼端等待着你
She will be for you on the other side.
你需要做的就是...
All you have to do...
进入那扇门
is enter.
大师? 大师? 能听到吗?
Maestro? Maestro? Can you hear me?
大师!
Maestro!
我们从昨晚就在找你 发生了什么事?
We've been looking for you since last night. What happened?
那个土耳其人当时在这儿
The Turk was here.
这儿原先还有... 还有一座雕像
There was... there was a statue.
是个祭坛
An altar.
得有一吨重
Must have weighed a ton.
里奥 这地方都荒废很久了
This place has been empty for centuries, Leo.
大师 夜巡官一直在找你
Maestro, the Officers of the Night have been searching for you.
他们说洛伦佐・美第奇本人要接见你
They say Lorenzo Medici himself has asked for you.
你是莱昂纳多・迪・瑟・皮耶罗...
Leonardo di ser Piero...
达芬奇
Da Vinci.
听说你是我公证员的私生子
I am told you are my notary's bastard son.
没错
I am.
我还听说你是个惹事精
I'm also told that you are a troublemaker,
傲慢自大 无视尊长...
you are arrogant, impolitic...
还完全不懂得保留自己的想法
and utterly incapable of keeping your opinions to yourself.
傲慢自大 说明我夸大了自己的价值
Arrogance implies that I exaggerate my own worth.
我没有
I don't.
我的女人 卢克蕾齐娅
My mistress, Lucrezia,
似乎觉得你有非凡的绘画天赋
seems to think that you have a singular talent for portraiture.
她坚持认为 除了你 没有人能够...
She insisted that you and none other be the one to...
捕捉到她的美貌
capture her beauty.
那我要说她有双识人的慧眼
I'd say she has a discerning eye, then.
长官 给您个警醒
A warning, sir.
这家伙只拿钱不干活是出了名的
The man has a reputation for taking many commissions, but finishing few.
我经常斟酌细节 所以容易厌烦
I wrestle with details. I bore easily.
这算是性格缺陷吧
Call it a character flaw.
接了这份活
Well, with this commission,
你最好能克服这个缺陷
you'd be wise to overcome it.
要画多纳蒂小姐的话
When it comes to Miss Donati,
我绝对不会感到厌烦
boredom is the last thing I fear.
那我就让你父亲起草合同啦
I'll have your father draw up a contract then.
长官 不知当讲不当讲 我还有些其他设计...
Sir, if I may, I have a few other designs...
有些设计 或许你会感兴趣
I have some designs that I think you might be interested in.
这将会极大地增强你手下炮手的火力
This will greatly increase your gunner's rate of firepower.
当上层的炮架发射弹药的同时
So, while the top rack's being fired,
下层的炮架可以装填弹药
the rack below that one can be loaded
再下层的炮架就有时间冷却
and the rack below that one is allowed to cool.
炮管呈扇形排开 能够...
The cannons are arranged in a fan, which...
- 够了 达芬奇  - 这是一辆装甲车
- That will be enough. Da Vinci.   - This is an armored cart.
由两名藏在其中的士兵推动
Propulsion is achieved by two men, who are housed within.
通过转动曲柄 带动车轮前进
They operate cranks, which rotate the wheels.
炮管可以安置在车的四周
Cannons can be mounted around the perimeter of the cart.
这是架飞行机器
It's a flying machine.
仿自蝙蝠铰接式的翅膀
It's modeled after the articulated wings of a bat.
疯了 如果人要能飞的话...
Madness. If man were meant to fly...
那生来就该有翅膀 没错
He would have been born with wings. Yes.
但是人类发明火药 以及其他的一些发明之前 甚至发现火之前
But a similar assertion could have been made prior to the invention of gunpowder
也有人有类似的论断吧
or any other invention conceived since fire.
我相信人类能征服蓝天 我之所以这么认为
I believe man will fly and I base this assumption
是因为上帝给了我们思想
on the fact that God has blessed us
能够想象的大脑
with minds that are capable of imagining it.
人们所梦想的一切 最终都能实现
Anything that can be dreamt of will eventually be built.
不同意我的人 都是傻子
Anyone who says otherwise is a fool.
你到底想干什么?
What exactly do you propose?
我想受雇...
I wish to be employed...
成为军事工程师
as a military engineer.
达芬奇 我是个人道主义者
I am a humanist, Da Vinci.
我无意发动战争
I have no interest in waging war.
但正是由于你的人道主义 才会发生战争
And yet your humanism is precisely why war will happen.
弗罗伦萨没有常备军
Florence has no standing army.
罗马也没有
Nor does Rome.
出于需要...
Necessarily...
你们都和拥有常备军的国家结了盟
you've both made alliances with states that do.
弗洛伦萨和米兰结盟
Florence with Milan,
罗马和纳普勒斯结盟
and Rome with Naples.
斯福尔扎遇刺 颠覆了游戏规则
Sforza's death has up-ended the game board.
殿下 您需要属于自己的武器
You need weapons of your own, Your Magnificence.
我给你一笔合适的经费
I will give you a modest stipend.
看这些能否...
To see whether these...
你的这些奇妙装置能否最终实现
contraptions of yours can actually be realized.
- 给100佛罗林如何?  - 50
- Shall we say 100 florins?  - 50.
你再讨价还价 我就割下你的舌头
If you haggle any further, I'll cut out your tongue.
您说了算 长官
As you say, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
你利用卢克蕾齐娅来接近我 对吧?
You used Lucrezia to gain access to me, didn't you?
我会利用一切手段
I utilize any device at my disposal,
来实现我的目标
in order to realize my goals.
聪明
Clever,
但我警告你 替我干活 别聪明过头了
but I'd caution you not to be too clever around me.
钟表的内部构造
Clockwork loses its luster,
只要被看穿 也就会失去魅力
once one glimpses the gears beneath its face.
您说得对
Point taken.
有什么问题吗?
Is there a problem?
没有 长官
None at all, sir.
再见
Good day.
- 祝贺你 莱昂纳多  - 消息传得真快
- Congratulations, Leonardo.  - Word travels fast.
弗洛伦萨哪有什么秘密
Ah, there are no secrets in Florence.
你到底怎么做到的呢?
How the devil did you do it?
哦 他利用了一个女人的虚荣
Oh, he played on a woman's vanity.
你个混蛋 你的计谋我们看得一清二楚
Your stratagem has become clear, you bastard.
他是一流的混蛋
A bastard of the highest order.
哈! 大伙干杯
Ha! Drink up everybody.
之后回去工作 我们还得做只焰鸽呢!
Then get back to work. We've got a colombina to build!
你去把被绞死犹太人的尸体挖出来
The Jew that was hanged, I want you to unearth his body.
我要检查检查
I need to examine it.
给我什么报酬?
And my compensation?
得看尸体烂成什么样了
Well, that depends how fresh the corpse is.
那我最好现在就开挖
Ah, well, then, I'd best get digging.
帕锡家族来了
Ah, here's the Pazzi clan.
还有他们的阴谋家弗朗西斯科和老男人雅各布
With their schemer Francesco and old man Jacopo.
可能是佛罗伦萨最老的家族
Probably the oldest family in Florence,
但绝对是地位最低的
definitely the most ornery.
帕锡家族委托洛伦佐・德・美第奇
The Pazzi family entrusts Lorenzo de Medici
将这束新火
with this new fire,
插在圣墓大教堂的石座上
struck on stones from the Church of the Holy Sepulcher.
以行使我们的权力
As is our right.
行使我们祖先在第一次十字军东征时
Granted to our ancestor for his actions
所获得的权力
during the First Crusade.
焰鸽即将翱翔
The colombina is about to fly.
欢迎你们所有人来到上帝之家
Welcome, all of you, into God's home.
凤凰的火焰和你很配
The flames of the phoenix suit you well.
老实告诉我
Tell me, truly,
你对和你上床的妓女们 都这么念念不忘吗?
are you always this wistful with the whores you bed?
哦 你不是妓女 夫人
Oh, you are no whore, Signora.
没必要再装下去了 多纳蒂小姐
We need not continue this pretence any longer, Miss Donati.
从你接近我的一开始我就知道是你
I knew it was you from the moment you approached me.
你怎么知道的?
How did you know?
我画过你
I sketched you.
一颦一笑 一动一静 一言一行
Your features, your form, your bearing.
更重要的是...
The more salient question...
为何高贵如你
is why would a noblewoman
却不惜自毁名誉委身于一个低贱的画师呢?
risk her reputation on a lowly artisan?
这不是狂欢的意义吗?
Well, isn't that the point of a carnival?
装作你不是你自己 然后一夜风流
To pretend, for a night, that you're someone you're not.
不 我觉得不止这样
No, I think there's more to it than that, yeah.
那说给我听听
Tell me, then.
你被我的画迷住了
You were intrigued by my sketch.
对 所以...
Yeah, so...
你感觉它勾勒出了你的另一面
You felt that it captured an aspect of yourself
这是你的丈夫 你的情人洛伦佐
that remains hidden from your husband,
都没有发现的
and from your lover, Lorenzo.
而你也只是在...
The only time you see this aspect...
照镜子的时候
is on the rare occasions
才看到自己的另一面
that you glimpse yourself in the mirror,
镜中的你 仿佛一个陌生人 回看着自己
and you find a stranger staring back at you.
你知道我会再把你找出来
You knew I'd seek you out, then.
哈...
Well...
嘿 我试着先发现人们行为的动机
Hey, I try to work out what motivates people
然后就顺水推舟
and then I proceed accordingly.
你掌控他们
You manipulate them.
不 我更愿意看做是 稍微地
No. I prefer to think of it as gently
把他们重新找回自己
redirecting their trajectories.
洛伦佐对你的设计很感兴趣
Lorenzo was quite taken with your designs.
我可以看一下这些奇迹吗?
Well, may I see one of these marvels?
这是什么?
What is it?
这是一个减慢下降速度的装置
It's a device for slowing one's rate of descent.
- 哦  - 嗯
- Oh.  - Yeah.
那我什么时候才可能用到它呢?
And under what circumstances would I possibly have use for this?
比方说你被困在堡垒里
Say that you were trapped in a fortress.
- 堡垒?  - 被攻陷的堡垒
- A fortress?  - A fortress that had been breached.
你可以这个绑在身上...
You could strap yourself into this...
就能安全落地 重获自由
and you'd safely float down to freedom.
哦 谢谢老天
Oh, thank goodness.
难怪洛伦佐对会你这么感兴趣
It would appear Lorenzo's interest in you was justified.
不过告诉我
But tell me.
我冒着身败名裂的险和你同床
I have risked my reputation by sleeping with you.
你付出了更大的代价
You've risked more.
说不定是生命
Perhaps even death.
我这么不顾一切 你觉得是为什么?
And to what do you ascribe my reckless behavior, then?
爱
Love.
别开玩笑了
Don't be absurd.
过目难忘 画眉描香 日思夜想
You saw me, you drew me, you fell in love.
就这么简单
It's as simple as that.
事实上我就是禁果
Add in the fact that I am forbidden fruit...
你命中注定爱上我
and your fate was sealed.
你是这星期第三个跟我说命运的人
You're the third person this week to lecture me on fate.
也许这正是你该听的时候
Well, perhaps it's time you started listening.
现在...
Now...
再和我做一次 莱昂纳多
Fuck me again, Leonardo.
这次 记好了...
This time, remember...
你不是唯一一个有掌控权的人
you're not the only one capable of manipulation.
这密令只对
The Secret Archives are open
教皇最亲近的顾问开放
only to his Holiness' closest advisors.
显然 我们不能让你进前面的门了
For obvious reasons, we can't have you parading through the front door.
啊
Ah.
真是失礼了
How rude of me.
我答应过要先给你报酬
I promised you your payment first.
你满意了?
I take it you're satisfied?
陛下
Your Eminence,
我从佛罗伦萨带来了消息
I bring news from Florence.
那就快点说
Get on with it, then.
有个新人出现了
A new player has entered the stage.
一个叫做莱昂纳多・达芬奇的画师
An artist known as Leonardo Da Vinci.
美第奇家族雇他设计攻城武器
The Medicis have employed him to design siege weapons.
画师就跟宫廷弄臣一样普通
Artists are as common as court jesters.
我看不出这个消息哪里关系到我们
I see no reason why this news should concern us.
这个画师不一样 他的想法都...
This artist is different. His ideas are...
不同寻常
unusual,
富有革新意义
revolutionary.
这是我在佛罗伦萨的线人
My agent in Florence.
你相信一个女人的情报?
You trust your intelligence to a woman?
当要传递情报时
When one seeks to convey a message,
我更愿意选择容易被忽视的人
I prefer to use vessels others would readily dismiss.
要是我没看错 你就是卢珀・梅克里
If I am not mistaken, you are Lupo Mercuri,
密令的管理人
Curator of the Secret Archives.
- 这有什么关系?  - 你也许会有兴趣
- What of it?  - It may interest you to know
达芬奇已经接触过了...
that Da Vinci has made contact...
那个土耳其人
with the Turk.
他在找一个叫"叶之书"的东西
He's searching for something called the Book of Leaves.
似乎土耳其人找到了新的守护神
It would appear the Turk has found a new champion.
继续监视他
Continue watching him.
看能不能收拢他
See if he can be co-opted.
要是不能呢?
And if he can't?
那达芬奇将陷入
Then Da Vinci will be consumed
炽热恐惧的地狱
in the fiery sorrows of hell
如同上帝的敌人一样
along with the rest of God's enemies.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 潇妹纸
时间轴: 潇妹纸
翻译: 苏菲 Being 潇妹纸 戴蜀
校对: 岸 从OSU滚蛋的雕